<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | C.M. Gienger</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/hank.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research involves investigating the diverse ways in which organisms interact with their environment. I am generally interested in how environmental constraints such as temperature, energy acquisition, and water balance influence behavior, life-history, and ecology. Most of the work that I do focuses on the ecology and natural history of amphibians and reptiles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Ford</title>
      <link>/authors/robert-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/robert-ford/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/ciafre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/ciafre/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/clinger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/clinger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Energetic costs of reproduction in Eastern Box Turtles (Terrapene carolina).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/flaherty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/flaherty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Effects of fire management on the ecology of Copperhead snakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/fulbright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/fulbright/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APSU thesis research investigated habitat selection of cottonmouth snakes (Agkistrodon piscivorous).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/hromada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/hromada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My primary research interest is the conservation of biodiversity.  I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in how land management practices impact faunal diversity patterns and occupancy of rare species. My thesis focused on understanding the impacts of using controlled burns to restore Oak Savanna habitat on reptile and amphibian community assemblages at Land Between the Lakes National Recreation Area in Kentucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hromada, S.J., C.A.F. Howey, M.B. Dickinson, R.W. Perry, W.M. Roosenberg, and C.M. Gienger. 2018. Response of reptile and amphibian communities to the reintroduction of fire in an oak/hickory forest. Forest Ecology and Management 428:1-13.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/iacchetta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/iacchetta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research interests focus on the behavior and ecology of reptiles and amphibians with goal of informing management and conservation decisions for species and their critical habitat. More specifically, I am interested in how natural and anthropogenic habitat alterations effect species survival and fitness. My thesis research focused on the effects of fire-altered habitat on the stress physiology and ecology of the Eastern Fence Lizard (Sceloporus undulatus).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iacchetta, M.G., K.N. Maloney, and C.M. Gienger. 2019. Endocrine stress response of Eastern Fence Lizards in fire-disturbed landscapes. Current Zoology (in press). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/cz/zoy092&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/cz/zoy092&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/kauphusman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/kauphusman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research interests include spatial ecology of reptiles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/mueller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/mueller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research interests include the ecology, physiology, and conservation of reptiles and amphibians.  I am also interested in the management of both native and invasive species, particularly the impacts that invasive species have on native communities. My thesis research focused on understanding the thermal ecology of copperheads (Agkistrodon contortrix), a widespread North American viperid snake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mueller, A. and C.M. Gienger. 2019. Comparative thermal ecology of Copperheads (Agkistrodon contortrix) and Cottonmouths (Agkistrodon piscivorus). Journal of Thermal Biology 79:73-80.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spencer, M.M., Mueller, A. and C.M. Gienger. 2017. A novel safety shield design to assist with handling venomous snakes. Herpetology Notes 10:487-489.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/pierson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/pierson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research interests include spatial ecology of reptiles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/richard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/richard/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/spencer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/spencer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have an interest in behavioral, physiological, invasive, and conservation herpetology. Currently I am interested in comparative physiology within the family viperidae. I am also interested in studying invasive reptile impacts and interactions with native species. My thesis research is directed at comparison of energetics between species of viperid snakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spencer, M.M., Mueller, A. and C.M. Gienger. 2017. A novel safety shield design to assist with handling venomous snakes. Herpetology Notes 10:487-489.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/thiem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/thiem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research interests include spatial ecology of reptiles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/wild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wild, K.H. and C.M. Gienger. 2018. Fire-disturbed landscapes induce phenotypic plasticity in lizard locomotor performance. Journal of Zoology 305(2):96-105.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
